<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <title>Notes</title>
  <subtitle>Just a bunch of ramblings or blog posts.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://thecrafters001.com/notes/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://thecrafters001.com/" />
  <updated>2025-07-09T20:41:39Z</updated>
  <id>https://thecrafters001.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>TheCrafters001</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Reverse Engineering Ghost Toolbox</title>
    <link href="https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2025/7/9/reverse-engineering-code/" />
    <updated>2025-07-09T20:41:39Z</updated>
    <id>https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2025/7/9/reverse-engineering-code/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;I will not be surprised if any of what I talk about in this post gets changed, I just thought it was cool.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It all started with me wanting to figure out what kind of tool a custom Windows ISO was using to download stuff like FireFox or Chrome. I wanted to see if I could make my own version of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I tried looking for some python tool that I remember from one of them, but I couldn&#39;t find it. So I decided to install the OS that I knew had something like that and oh wow did that ever send me down a rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Ghost Spectre&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I decided to install the OS that I knew had a tool, as I mentioned above. It took me a while to actually even download the ISO, which was its own mess that I don&#39;t want to go through again, nor will I discuss how to download it as this is not what this post is for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I installed Ghost Spectre into a VM using VMWare, which gives me a safe space to mess around with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;quote warning&quot;&gt;I want to point out that installing a custom Windows ISO can put you at risk to getting malware. &lt;b&gt;DO NOT&lt;/b&gt; install custom Windows ISOs unless you either know what you are doing, or know what you are going to get into.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once I Ghost Spectre (which I will just be calling &amp;quot;Ghost&amp;quot; from here on out), I quickly located where the tool&#39;s EXE was located, the tool being called &amp;quot;Ghost Toolbox&amp;quot;, which I will just call &amp;quot;Toolbox&amp;quot;. I ended up finding the toolbox in &lt;code&gt;C:&#92;Ghost Toolbox&#92;&lt;/code&gt; and there were 2 files, and a folder. One file was the actual EXE called &lt;code&gt;toolbox.updater.x64.exe&lt;/code&gt;, a config called &lt;code&gt;toolbox.updater.x64.config&lt;/code&gt;, and the folder was called &lt;code&gt;wget&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;A screenshot of the Windows File Explorer, showing 3 items listed. In order, they are: &#39;wget&#39;, &#39;toolbox.updater.x64.config&#39; and &#39;toolbox.updater.x64.exe&#39;&quot; src=&quot;https://thecrafters001.com/asset/img/post-assets/rev-eng-ghost/toolboxLocated.png&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I run the program, I see a CLI application open, followed by PowerShell and &lt;abbr title=&quot;Command Prompt&quot;&gt;CMD&lt;/abbr&gt; open, which contains the actual toolbox.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;A screenshot of Ghost Toolbox&#39;s Main Menu&quot; src=&quot;https://thecrafters001.com/asset/img/post-assets/rev-eng-ghost/toolboxMenu.png&quot;&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Looking in the Program&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I thought, since it is just running the Command Prompt, that it has to be a batch script running somewhere. I downloaded Sysinternals &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/sysinternals/downloads/procmon&quot;&gt;Process Monitor (Procmon)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/sysinternals/downloads/process-explorer&quot;&gt;Process Explorer&lt;/a&gt; to explore what exactly the program was doing. As I watched, I noticed in Procmon that the toolbox EXE kept executing CMD, which tells me that it is indeed just running a script file (often called a Batch file) somewhere on the system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At that point, I opened Process Explorer, which is pretty much Task Manager but on steroids. Once I opened it, I closed the toolbox and re-ran it. As it was executing, I froze Process Explorer, making it so it doesn&#39;t update, and I was right, it was indeed running a CMD window... and I could see one of many arguments that most likely were running. It is at this point, I downloaded another Sysinternals tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/sysinternals/downloads/strings&quot;&gt;Strings&lt;/a&gt;, which pretty much allows me to view all the strings in a program (who would have guessed). I ran it on the program and got a lot of garbage, but as the output was going by, I noticed a few long strings that looked interesting, so I redirected the output of strings to a text file, and after filtering out all the garbage, I found what I was looking for, a set of command line instructions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The string of code I found was the following:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;%COMSPEC% /c del /q /f wget&#92;update &amp;gt;nul 2&amp;gt;nul
%COMSPEC% /c del /a /q /f %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;run.ghost.cmd &amp;gt;nul 2&amp;gt;nul
%COMSPEC% /c wget&#92;wget.exe -q --backups=1 http://xcazy.the-ninja.jp/update/2021/x64/toolbox.update -t 0 -O wget&#92;update &amp;gt;nul 2&amp;gt;nul
%COMSPEC% /c timeout /t 1 &amp;gt;nul 2&amp;gt;nul
%COMSPEC% /c wget&#92;7z1900-extra&#92;x64&#92;7za x wget&#92;update -aoa -pghostX2021 -o%Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests &amp;gt;nul 2&amp;gt;nul
%COMSPEC% /c del /a /q /f %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;wbem&#92;en-US&#92;update.cmd &amp;gt;nul 2&amp;gt;nul
%COMSPEC% /c timeout /t 1 &amp;gt;nul 2&amp;gt;nul
%COMSPEC% /c rename %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;toolbox.cmd run.ghost.cmd &amp;gt;nul 2&amp;gt;nul
%COMSPEC% /c attrib +S +H +R %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;run.ghost.cmd &amp;gt;nul 2&amp;gt;nul
%COMSPEC% /c %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;run.ghost.cmd &amp;gt;nul 2&amp;gt;nul
%COMSPEC% /c del /q /f wget&#92;update &amp;gt;nul 2&amp;gt;nul
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Okay... thats a lot, let&#39;s take a little bit to break that down... &lt;code&gt;%COMSPEC%&lt;/code&gt; is a variable in the command prompt built into Windows, which just points to where CMD is and &lt;code&gt;/c&lt;/code&gt; just tells it to execute a command before closing. So I am just going to ignore that. And you may have noticed at the end of all commands the text &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;nul 2&amp;gt;nul&lt;/code&gt;, which tells the command prompt to not tell you what is going on, making programs that are otherwise &amp;quot;loud&amp;quot; silent, not putting out an output. So now that we know that, the commands look more like this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;del /q /f wget&#92;update 
del /a /q /f %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;run.ghost.cmd 
wget&#92;wget.exe -q --backups=1 http://xcazy.the-ninja.jp/update/2021/x64/toolbox.update -t 0 -O wget&#92;update 
timeout /t 1 
wget&#92;7z1900-extra&#92;x64&#92;7za x wget&#92;update -aoa -pghostX2021 -o%Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests 
del /a /q /f %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;wbem&#92;en-US&#92;update.cmd 
timeout /t 1 
rename %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;toolbox.cmd run.ghost.cmd 
attrib +S +H +R %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;run.ghost.cmd 
%Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;run.ghost.cmd 
del /q /f wget&#92;update 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another thing we should filter out is the commands that are called &lt;code&gt;timeout&lt;/code&gt;, which simply just tell the command prompt to wait a specific amount of time before running the rest of the script, removing those we get:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;del /q /f wget&#92;update 
del /a /q /f %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;run.ghost.cmd 
wget&#92;wget.exe -q --backups=1 http://xcazy.the-ninja.jp/update/2021/x64/toolbox.update -t 0 -O wget&#92;update 
wget&#92;7z1900-extra&#92;x64&#92;7za x wget&#92;update -aoa -pghostX2021 -o%Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests 
del /a /q /f %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;wbem&#92;en-US&#92;update.cmd 
rename %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;toolbox.cmd run.ghost.cmd 
attrib +S +H +R %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;run.ghost.cmd 
%Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;run.ghost.cmd 
del /q /f wget&#92;update 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Breaking it down&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s start to break this down line by line and bit by bit, starting with &lt;code&gt;del /q /f wget&#92;update&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;del&lt;/code&gt; is a command short for Delete in Windows, so it is safe to assume that we are going to delete a file. &lt;code&gt;/q&lt;/code&gt; makes it so it doesn&#39;t put an output into the prompt, which in this case, would just be hiding &amp;quot;The operation has completed.&amp;quot; or something similar. &lt;code&gt;/f&lt;/code&gt; means to forcfully delete something, no matter what. Finally, &lt;code&gt;wget&#92;update&lt;/code&gt; is a path, where &lt;code&gt;wget&#92;&lt;/code&gt; is a folder and &lt;code&gt;update&lt;/code&gt; is a file. So the command is telling Windows to delete a file called &lt;code&gt;update&lt;/code&gt; in the folder &lt;code&gt;wget&lt;/code&gt;... Interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next line (&lt;code&gt;del /a /q /f %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;run.ghost.cmd&lt;/code&gt;) does something similar, only changing out the path for &lt;code&gt;%Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;run.ghost.cmd&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;wget&#92;update&lt;/code&gt;. Interesting, that tells me that the file we are running is stored in the folder called &lt;code&gt;C:&#92;Windows&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;&lt;/code&gt;, as &lt;code&gt;%windir%&lt;/code&gt; is another system variable that points to &lt;code&gt;C:&#92;Windows&#92;&lt;/code&gt;... But when I try visiting the folder, I don&#39;t see a file named &lt;code&gt;run.ghost.cmd&lt;/code&gt;, which is a batch file... Strange, let&#39;s keep breaking this down...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next line (&lt;code&gt;wget&#92;wget.exe -q --backups=1 http://xcazy.the-ninja.jp/update/2021/x64/toolbox.update -t 0 -O wget&#92;update&lt;/code&gt;) is interesting, as we are running a program called &lt;code&gt;wget&lt;/code&gt;, which is a simple program to download files from the internet. We see a similar argument to hide the output as before called &lt;code&gt;-q&lt;/code&gt;, so removing that will show us the output should we run &lt;code&gt;wget&lt;/code&gt; on it&#39;s own. We will be ignoring the backups part as it isn&#39;t relevent here. Next we see a URL, which makes sense since we are pulling a file from the internet... when I tried visiting it the first time, I thought it would have blocked me because I am not downloading it from the toolbox itself... but no! It actually downloads the file in my browser. I was really interested in this file... but let&#39;s keep breaking down this command. &lt;code&gt;-t 0&lt;/code&gt; tells &lt;code&gt;wget&lt;/code&gt; to just keep retrying infinitely should it fail. Finally, &lt;code&gt;-O wget&#92;update&lt;/code&gt; tells &lt;code&gt;wget&lt;/code&gt; to store the file in the &lt;code&gt;wget&lt;/code&gt; folder, and call the file &lt;code&gt;update&lt;/code&gt;. Let&#39;s keep looking and see what it does next...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next command it runs is &lt;code&gt;wget&#92;7z1900-extra&#92;x64&#92;7za x wget&#92;update -aoa -pghostX2021 -o%Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&lt;/code&gt;. The start of it, &lt;code&gt;wget&#92;7z1900-extra&#92;x64&#92;7za&lt;/code&gt; is telling us that the program is now running a archive program called &lt;code&gt;7za&lt;/code&gt;, which is part of &lt;a href=&quot;https://7-zip.org/&quot;&gt;7-Zip&lt;/a&gt;. The next part is an argument called &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt;, which is short for extract in &lt;code&gt;7za&lt;/code&gt;. So we are going to be extracting something... interesting. The next part is &lt;code&gt;wget&#92;update&lt;/code&gt;, which is the file that &lt;code&gt;wget&lt;/code&gt; just saved. Really interesting! That tells us that the file we just downloaded is actually just an archive! And opening it with 7-zip does indeed confirm that, with a file inside if it simply called &lt;code&gt;toolbox.cmd&lt;/code&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;A screenshot of 7-zip, showing the contents of the &#39;update&#39; file mentioned above&quot; src=&quot;https://thecrafters001.com/asset/img/post-assets/rev-eng-ghost/7zip.png&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;But when I tried extracting it, it requires a password... dang... Let&#39;s keep digging at that command for more clues then... The next part of the command is &lt;code&gt;-aoa&lt;/code&gt;, which tells &lt;code&gt;7za&lt;/code&gt; to overwrite all files, without prompting for any user input... in this case, it is kind of useless as we deleted the files before. The next argument is &lt;code&gt;-pghostX2021&lt;/code&gt;... That looks strange... but checking the arguments for 7za, &lt;code&gt;-p&lt;/code&gt; is short for password, meaning if we remove the &lt;code&gt;-p&lt;/code&gt; at the start, we are left with &lt;code&gt;ghostX2021&lt;/code&gt;, and when I try extracting the archive now, with that password, it works! But before we get too excited, let&#39;s keep looking at the last part of the command... &lt;code&gt;-o%Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&lt;/code&gt;, oh look at that! It extracts out the file to the folder we deleted &lt;code&gt;run.ghost.cmd&lt;/code&gt; from! But that doesn&#39;t answer why it is called something different right now...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But before we finish up with the rest of it, here is all the commands we have gone though so far:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;del /q /f wget&#92;update 
del /a /q /f %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;run.ghost.cmd 
wget&#92;wget.exe -q --backups=1 http://xcazy.the-ninja.jp/update/2021/x64/toolbox.update -t 0 -O wget&#92;update 
wget&#92;7z1900-extra&#92;x64&#92;7za x wget&#92;update -aoa -pghostX2021 -o%Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s a lot! And mostly all we needed to get the actual script I wanted to see, the rest of the commands,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;del /a /q /f %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;wbem&#92;en-US&#92;update.cmd 
rename %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;toolbox.cmd run.ghost.cmd 
attrib +S +H +R %Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;run.ghost.cmd 
%Windir%&#92;System32&#92;migwiz&#92;dlmanifests&#92;run.ghost.cmd 
del /q /f wget&#92;update 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;go through the process of renaming the file (&lt;code&gt;toolbox.cmd&lt;/code&gt;) to &lt;code&gt;run.ghost.cmd&lt;/code&gt; and making it so the file is hidden, meaning we cannot see it unless we tell windows we want to see hidden files, then running the file. And before all that, it tried to delete a file that doesn&#39;t exist so I have no idea what&#39;s going on there... and then once the program starts running, it deletes the &lt;code&gt;wget&#92;update&lt;/code&gt; archive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Success!&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We now have the file I wanted to get, &lt;code&gt;toolbox.cmd&lt;/code&gt;! And now I can look at what it is trying to do! We have figured out where the file is downloaded from, figured out that it is a password protected archive, found the password hidden in plain text in the program itself, and have successfully extracted it from the archive using the password!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was a fun little side project I did, and it actually was my first time doing any serious reverse engineering, so I learned some things doing this!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed this as much as I did! Feel free to discuss everything in the comments below, I would love to see what you would have done differently or would have tried!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Expanding my Self-Hosted Web Services</title>
    <link href="https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2025/7/1/extending-linkstack/" />
    <updated>2025-07-01T17:30:33Z</updated>
    <id>https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2025/7/1/extending-linkstack/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been wanting to expand my self-hosted web services. I am currently limited by hardware and storage, so I can&#39;t run anything like NextCloud (not for lots of storage at least, plus my self-host server tends to have a lot of instability right now that I am working on, which is why it has been going down lately), but I am looking for ideas. If anyone has any suggestions, let me know below!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>This Blog will change to more of a &#39;Notebook&#39; style page.</title>
    <link href="https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2025/4/29/blog-changes/" />
    <updated>2025-04-29T04:19:53Z</updated>
    <id>https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2025/4/29/blog-changes/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have wanted to post thinges here for a long time that are kinda outside the realm of &amp;quot;blog&amp;quot; style posts. So I have decided to change this from &amp;quot;Blog&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;Notebook&amp;quot; or something like that. At some point I will change the link in the navbar too to match the change, but right now I am gonna leave it as it is.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Migrating to 11ty</title>
    <link href="https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2025/1/27/migrating-to-11ty/" />
    <updated>2025-01-28T03:31:04Z</updated>
    <id>https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2025/1/27/migrating-to-11ty/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So yeah. I migrated to 11ty, since, as you can see, I am given greater control over how I want to make my website. It allows me to be more free by using my own HTML templates. For example, I can have my &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecrafters001.com/pages.html&quot;&gt;All Pages&lt;/a&gt; template below, or even, my navigation bar at the top in the post here as well - Just as a few examples. Now does that mean I will include these on every page? No, not at all, given that it will sometimes break the site. But at least I have the freedom to do those things now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Main Pages&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table style=&quot;max-width: 700px !important;&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;top-bar&quot;&gt;Page Name&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;top-bar&quot;&gt;Page Link&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;top-bar&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;Home&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecrafters001.com/index.html&quot;&gt;/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;Software&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecrafters001.com/software/index.html&quot;&gt;/software/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;I make programs!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;Games&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecrafters001.com/games/index.html&quot;&gt;/games/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;I make &quot;games&quot;!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecrafters001.com/blog/&quot;&gt;/blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;I write things!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;PC Specs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecrafters001.com/pc-specs.html&quot;&gt;/pc-specs.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;I do gaming!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;All Pages&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecrafters001.com/pages.html&quot;&gt;/pages.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;content-page&quot;&gt;You are here.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>So Nintendo Filed a Lawsuit Against PocketPair</title>
    <link href="https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2024/9/19/nintendo-pocketpair-lawsuit/" />
    <updated>2024-09-19T04:23:47Z</updated>
    <id>https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2024/9/19/nintendo-pocketpair-lawsuit/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;https://thecrafters001.com/asset/img/post-heros/nintendo-pocketpair-lawsuit.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nintendo and The Pokémon Company has decided to throw a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nintendo.co.jp/corporate/release/en/2024/240919.html&quot;&gt;Patent lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; at PocketPair, the developers of Palworld. Honestly, I understand why Nintendo would want to sue Palworld, as it uses mechanics akin to catching Pokémon, but outside of that, I feel like Palworld is a completely different game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palworld is quite fun in my opinion. It has interesting gameplay, and feels like its own thing compaired to Pokémon. I honestly don&amp;#39;t think that Nintendo will win, however, I know dang well that they will try to fight that lawsuit to the end, giving PocketPair a lawyer nightmare&amp;#39;s worth of paperwork and money thrown their way. Though, I find it interesting how Nintendo won&amp;#39;t go after the countless other knock-offs that are on Steam as well, such as Temtem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If PocketPair were to lose the lawsuit, I doubt that it would matter much honestly, I still feel like Palworld will hold some sort of presence now that it is out there. Weather or not Nintendo actually succeeds in their lawsuit ventures, I have no idea, but I feel like Palworld and PocketPair will stay around for a while.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As for the countless other controversies involving Palworld, I will not comment on, as I don&amp;#39;t care about them much. I enjoy the game for what it is, and I don&amp;#39;t want to feel bad for playing a game I enjoy. Plus, surrounding yourself in drama is not good for your mental health. Negativity is a bad thing, you know.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Retrospring - End of Life</title>
    <link href="https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2024/8/27/retrospring-eol/" />
    <updated>2024-08-27T06:48:57Z</updated>
    <id>https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2024/8/27/retrospring-eol/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Retrospring, a way to ask questions to users for them to answer, is getting shut down on the 1st of March 2025. I used Retrospring to answer a few questions ask to me, whether it was from an anon user, or a user I knew, I tried to answer them. However, with the light of the closure of Retrospring in the future, I plan to find another way for others to ask questions to me. Right now, I have a pretty much fresh Tumblr account I don&amp;#39;t use for much, I have opened up questions there, so if you want, you can ask me questions there for now. Here is the link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tumblr.com/new/ask/thecrafters001&quot; title=&quot;Link to ask questions on Tumblr.&quot;&gt;https://www.tumblr.com/new/ask/thecrafters001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Until Retrospring shuts down, my shortlink I made (&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecrafters001.github.io/links/ask&quot; title=&quot;Link to ask questions on Retrospring.&quot;&gt;https://thecrafters001.github.io/links/ask&lt;/a&gt;) will remain up. After the shutdown, however, it will be changed to link to this blog post, tumblr, or whatever other service I find. I know Tumblr isn&amp;#39;t the best option, as you need to create an account, even to ask as anon, something Retrospring didn&amp;#39;t require, so I will be looking for alternatives. I will update this blog post later if I do end up finding a new service and link that here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Until then, you can keep asking me questions on Retrospring until the service gets shut down.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Essentials Team Builder - Open-source Team Building</title>
    <link href="https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2024/7/11/essential-team-builder/" />
    <updated>2024-07-11T07:30:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2024/7/11/essential-team-builder/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;https://thecrafters001.com/asset/img/software/EssentialsTeamBuilder.png&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A little bit ago, I released the initial version of Essentials Team Builder (ETB) on GitHub and Eevee Expo. It isn&amp;#39;t perfect, but it solves a personal pet peeve I have. I very much dislike the built-in editor to Essentials, and this tool pretty much aims to be that, but in a more user-friendly UI. With this upgrade from Showdown to Essentials Converter (StEC) comes a brand new UI, as well as a more optimized codebase. ETB uses a lot less code than what StEC did before, as initially, StEC had almost 2000 lines of code for JUST the code generation. With ETB, I compacted the generator into its own script which has just under 300 lines of code, and the calls it can receive can be done in as few as 1 line per entry!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On top of that, there also was a major code migration as during the initial development, StEC was using .NET Framework, but has since to moved to .NET, meaning it uses a more well structured code base, as well as taking up less space! And, on top of all of that, I managed to migrate it from version-to-version of Essentials, meaning I can handle Essentials 17, all the way up to 20+, and I can add more to it as needed! Though, the change between the 17 codebase, 18 codebase, and 19 codebase was so dramatic I might end up having to create new functions for newer versions as well... Ah well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh, and the project is all open-source too! Feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TheCrafters001/essentials-team-builder&quot; title=&quot;Essentials Team Builder GitHub Page&quot;&gt;poke around the inner workings&lt;/a&gt; of the program, and suggest fixes! Or, if you wish, the program now supports multiple languages, feel free to fork and open a &lt;abbr title=&quot;Pull Request&quot;&gt;PR&lt;/abbr&gt; for your language!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Screenshot and Logo by TheCrafters001. This is a fan-made tool. Pokémon is not owned by TheCrafters001; Pokémon is owned by GAME FREAK Inc. This tool does not allow you to create your own fan-games, rather it is to help aid you. The Poké Ball symbol is a trademark of GAME FREAK Inc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Gift Art for eblu</title>
    <link href="https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2024/5/20/eblu-cobalt-art/" />
    <updated>2024-05-20T06:20:50Z</updated>
    <id>https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2024/5/20/eblu-cobalt-art/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;https://thecrafters001.com/asset/art/gift/eblu/cobalt_pixel_gift.png&quot; alt=&quot;A colorful ant that is happy and offering to give the viewer a hug!&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Art originally posted on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://meow.social/@TheCrafters001&quot; title=&quot;Mastodon Link&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; page on April 24, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Art for &lt;a href=&quot;https://eblu.space&quot; title=&quot;eblu homepage&quot;&gt;eblu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Guesses for Pokémon Legends: Z-A</title>
    <link href="https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2024/5/8/pokemon-za-guesses/" />
    <updated>2024-05-09T00:31:29Z</updated>
    <id>https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2024/5/8/pokemon-za-guesses/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;https://thecrafters001.com/asset/img/post-heros/pkmn-legends-za.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the up-coming Legends game in the Pokémon series, I thought that I may as well give some of my thoughts on it. If you didn&#39;t know, there is a new Pokémon game in the works over at GAME FREAK Inc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is the trailer if you have not seen it already.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/uq-Znr_jGIg&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;I thought I would share what I think could be a possibility of what may come in the game. Do know, that I could be wrong, and I could be right. There really is no way for me to know what is coming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Present to Past&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Knowing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://legends.arceus.pokemon.com/&quot; title=&quot;Legends Arcues Home Page&quot;&gt;last Legends game&lt;/a&gt; took place thousands of years in the past, I think it is safe to assume the &quot;Legends&quot; part of the name means &quot;Past.&quot; Knowing this, and what we know of &lt;a href=&quot;https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/AZ&quot; title=&quot;AZ - Bulbapedia&quot;&gt;AZ&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Ultimate_weapon&quot; title=&quot;Ultimate weapon - Bulbapedia&quot;&gt;Ultimate Weapon&lt;/a&gt;, I think Legends Z-A will take place roughly 3,000 years in the past, either right after, or shortly after the War of Kalos. With the game serving as the &quot;re-development&quot; of Lumiose City, I think it is safe to say that Lumiose was destroyed during the war, and the player would have to go around the aftermath of the war, helping rebuild Lumiose. But, I also think that, while yes the game mainly takes place in the former Lumiose City ruins, you also get to explore some places just outside the area, such as Routes 4, 5, 13, 14 and 16. Maybe you may be able to explore some of the other places in Kalos, but I am unsure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine also mentioned that, since Lumiose is based on Paris, France, that there could be an area based off the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Catacombs_of_Paris&quot; title=&quot;Catacombs of Paris - Wikipedia&quot;&gt;Catacombs of Paris&lt;/a&gt;, which I feel would be an interesting inclusion if they did decide to add it. Could it be the resting place of People and Pokémon? Or perhapse something else?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Long Lost Kingdom&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;AZ used to be the king of Kalos, so what if we get to see AZ directly after the events of the firing of the Ultimate Weapon? I think it could be an interesting thing they could do, given that we do not know much about the Kingdom that AZ once ruled over. Which also leads me into my next theory, what if Lumiose City used to be AZ&#39;s Kingdom? If so, what caused the war? What was the war trying to achive? Why was AZ so compelled to turn a machine that could once bring those back to life, and potentialy making them immortal, and turning it into a weapon of mass distruction? What was AZ&#39;s goal as a leader?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game is too far out to know, and with what little information we have, it is hard to know exactly what the game is about. But we also don&#39;t have a lot of answers as to what AZ&#39;s goal is. When we first meet him in X &amp; Y, we learn of him being the king of Kalos, and that he had the key to the Ultimate Weapon, before &lt;a href=&quot;https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Team_Flare&quot; title=&quot;Team Flare - Bulbapedia&quot;&gt;Team Flare&lt;/a&gt; took it by force. After we learn about this, AZ tells the player the story of the Ultimate Weapon at Lysandre Labs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/AZ#Quotes&quot;&gt;Listen, one who will face Lysandre… A terribly long time ago… There was a man and a Pokémon. He loved that Pokémon very much. A war began. The man&#39;s beloved Pokémon took part in the war. Several years passed. He was given a tiny box. The man wanted to bring the Pokémon back. No matter what it took. The man built a machine to give it life. He brought his beloved Pokémon back. The man had suffered too much. His rage had not subsided. He could not forgive the world that had hurt the Pokémon he loved. He turned the machine into the ultimate weapon. The man became a bringer of destruction that ended the war. The Pokémon that was given life must have known… That the lives of many Pokémon were taken to restore its life. The resurrected Pokémon left the man. Get the key back. It should not be used. Everything will vanish again. Do you want to know unending pain…like I have?&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;And at Geosenge Town.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/AZ#Quotes&quot;&gt;A long time ago. A very long time ago. The man made an ultimate weapon. Using it required the life force of many Pokémon… The Pokémon granted eternal life learned this. The resurrected eternal Pokémon left the man&#39;s side. The man was surprised and sad. He had revived it so they could be together… Day after day passed, but they were never to meet. Eventually, he became a mere shell of a man. A man condemned to wander forever by the light of the weapon… And a Pokémon that also wanders eternally… Where is it now? What do I have to do to meet it?&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beyond what he tells us nothing about the War, or his past life as a King.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Closing thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of these thoughts are just my personal thoughts or theories. I think it would be interesting to learn about the past of Kalos more, and to learn more about AZ, if at all. Of course, there is no way to know what we will get out of the game considering that it comes out in 2025, and GAME FREAK hasn&#39;t released much details to the public yet. Needless to say, I am excited for the new Legends game, and have higher than normal expectations for when it comes out! What do you think? I would like to hear yoru own opinions or thoughts on the upcoming game!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Pokémon Legends: Z-A Logo by Game Freak.&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Hugo Site</title>
    <link href="https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2024/4/27/my-hugo-site/" />
    <updated>2024-04-28T03:40:38Z</updated>
    <id>https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2024/4/27/my-hugo-site/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello! You may have noticed my new site&#39;s design! Well, this is now a personal blog. Again. It won&#39;t have much on here, sorry. Most of the time I will usually make posts only for software/game updates or other news.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I am still trying to migrate everything over, so please bare with me while I get everything moved over.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hello, World!</title>
    <link href="https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2024/4/26/hello-world/" />
    <updated>2024-04-26T06:18:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://thecrafters001.com/posts/2024/4/26/hello-world/</id>
    <content type="html">Hello, World!</content>
  </entry>
</feed>